Guide to the Police Advisory Board, Yale University, Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Police Advisory Board, Yale University, records
1961-1981
RU 1102
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
4.5
(9 boxes)
The materials consist of correspondence, reports, agendas and meeting minutes of the Police Advisory Board.
Yale University. Police Advisory Board
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 4-F (YRG 4-F), Records documenting Yale security.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The materials were transferred from the Office of the President, 1976; Office of of the Secretary, 1988.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the records is restricted. See Collection Contents for details.
Scope and Contents
The materials consist of correspondence, reports, agendas and meeting minutes of the Police Advisory Board.
Arrangement
The records are arranged by accession.
Campus police; Universities and colleges -- Security measures; Yale University. Police Advisory Board; Yale University. Police Dept
- Campus Police history project records, 1964-1971; Accession 1976-A-010; 1.5
  Conditions Governing Access
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2047.
  Scope and Contents
  The original inventory lists these records as "Campus Police History Project (JFF File)." JFF is probably Jonathan F. Fanton, Special Assistant to the President, who was a member of the Police Advisory Board. The records include crime reports, crime statistics, policies, correspondence, annual reports, arrests and incident reports concerning matters dealt with by the Police Advisory Board. Materials in these files are primarily addressed to Richard Carroll, Chair of Police Board, Henry Chauncey, Jr., Special Assistant to the President and Chair Police Board, and Jonathan Fanton.
  - General, 1967-1971 (Box 1)
  - Annual reports, 1966-1970 (Box 1)
  - Arrest reports
    - 1970-1972 (Box 1)
  - Budget, 1968-1972 (Box 2)
  - Campus police and the city, 1969-1970 (Box 2)
  - Chief, selection of, 1969-1970 (Box 2)
  - Commendation letters, 1970-1971 (Box 2)
  - Duties and functions, 1970-1971 (Box 2)
  - Electronic devices, 1969-1970 (Box 2)
  - Evening transportation, 1969-1970 (Box 2)
  - Furniture inventory, Undated (Box 2)
  - Governance Commission, 1970-1971 (Box 2)
  - Guards, 1969-1970 (Box 2)
  - Harvard trip, 1969-1970 (Box 2)
  - Law School security, 1969-1970 (Box 2)
  - Legal status, 1969-1970 (Box 2)
  - Mace use, 1970-1971 (Box 2)
  - Minority recruitment, 1967-1968 (Box 2)
  - Personnel, 1969-1971 (Box 3)
  - Police Board
    - General, 1964-1971 (Box 3)
    - Minutes of meetings, 1969-1971 (Box 3)
    - Student members, 1969-1970 (Box 3)
  - Police chiefs in Connecticut, 1970-1971 (Box 3)
  - Report on security at University of Wisconsin, 1969-1970 (Box 3)
  - Report on university locks, 1969-1970 (Box 3)
  - Security and college deans, 1969-1970 (Box 3)
  - Theft and arrest statistics, 1970-1971 (Box 3)
  - Thefts from colleges, Old Campus, and annexes, 1970 (Box 3)
  - Time of theft study, 1969-1970 (Box 3)
  - United Illuminating, 1969-1970 (Box 3)
  - Yale-New Haven Hospital, 1963-1970 (Box 3)
- Administrative records, 1968-1981; Accession 1988-A-030; 3
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2057.
  The bulk of the records appear to those of Lawrence Noble, Associate Secretary, who was an ex-officio member of the Police Advisory Board from 1973 to1981. Also includes records of Jonathan Fanton, Special Assistant to the President, who was a member of the Police Advisory Board. The records consist of reports, correspondence, agendas and meeting minutes of the Police Advisory Board, crime stats, and budgets. Reports, crime states, and budget materials seem to have been sent directly to the Secretary.
  - University Police
    - Director of Security, 1980 February 29 - April 10 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Keys, 1978 March 17 - 1979 March 6 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Legal Fees, 1975 September 25 - November 14 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Memoranda from the Chief, 1974 August 20 -1981 August 10 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Miscellaneous, 1973 June 18 - 1981 May 13 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Names Resevoir, 1974 May 24 - 1975 April 22 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Officer Training, 1976 December 15 - 1980 September 18 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Parking Lots, 1979 April 4 - May 22 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Pending, 1980 November 6 - 11 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Rating System, 1977 February - May 10 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Recidivism, 1976 March 15-1981 June 18 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Personnel, 1973 September 7-1981 March 31 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Reports from the Chief (Current Year), 1979 September 11 - 1981 August 19 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Reports from the Chief (Prior Years), 1973 June 22-1979 March 28 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Retirement, 1979 October 11-1981 June 12 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Security, 1974 January 31 - 1981 August 7 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Security Brochure, 1981 April 30 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Strike, 1974 April 23 - 1977 November 16 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Tuition Assistance Plan, 1973 September 5 - 1974 January 16 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Uniforms, 1976 February 19 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Yale Psychiatric Institute, 1974 February 21 - October 3 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Youth Assistance Program, 1974 April 15 - December 20 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Police Advisory Board, 1973-74, 1974 January 2 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Miscellaneous, 1972-73, 1972 September 14 - 1973 March 27 (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Police Advisory Board, 1972-73, 1972 October 10 - 1973 May 4 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Miscellaneous, 1971-72, 1971 June 2 - 1972 July 27 (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Police Advisory Board, 1971-72, 1971 July 22 - 1972 May 4 (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - 1970-1971, 1970 June 16-1970 December 17 (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Police Advisory Board, 1969-70, 1969 October 17 - 1971 April 19 (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - City of New Haven Police Department, 1969 November 3 - 1972 September 25 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Police Advisory Board
    - Agenda and Minutes (Current Year), 1979 November 21 - 1981 April 8 (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - Agenda and Minutes (Prior Years), 1973 June 1 - 1979 March 12 (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - Ammunition, 1975 Ju1 18 - 1977 February 25 (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - Complaints, 1975 May 28 - 1980 August 18 (Box 4, Folder 35)
    - Manual, 1974 January 1 - 1981 September 4 (Box 4, Folder 36 - 37)
    - Membership (Current Year), 1979 June 18-1981 June 11 (Box 4, Folder 38)
    - Membership (Prior Years), 1973 July 16-1978 December 12 (Box 4, Folder 39)
    - Miscellaneous, 1973 October 17-1979 April 24 (Box 4, Folder 40)
    - Pending, 1980 November 7-1981 June 6 (Box 4, Folder 41)
    - Statement of Purpose, 1975 November 4-1976 March 30 (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - University Police
    - Alarm Systems, 1980 June 17 - 1981 June 22 (Box 4, Folder 43)
    - Annual Reports, 1979 JuI - 1981 June (Box 5, Folder 44)
    - Automobile Leasing, 1978 May 17 - 1978 May 19 (Box 5, Folder 45)
    - University Benefits, 1981 March 4 (Box 5, Folder 46)
    - Budget Current, 1977 January 10 - 1981 May 21 (Box 5, Folder 47)
    - Budget Old, 1973 June 14 - 1977 May 18 (Box 5, Folder 48)
    - CARP, 1977 July 22 - 1979 February 5 (Box 5, Folder 49)
    - Chief, 1975 February 19 - 1980 May 23 (Box 5, Folder 50)
    - CIRRS, 1981 June 18 (Box 5, Folder 51)
    - Civil Service Commission, 1973 October 8 - 1975 March 11 (Box 5, Folder 52)
    - Commencement, 1981 April 20 (Box 5, Folder 53)
    - Complaints, 1978 December 7 - 1981 June 24 (Box 5, Folder 54)
    - Administration, 1973 June 23 - 1978 December 19 (Box 5, Folder 55)
    - Alarm Systems, 1977 February 9 - 1980 July 9 (Box 5, Folder 56)
    - Correspondence, 1973 August 20 - 1981 February 12 (Box 5, Folder 57)
    - Crime Prevention, 1975 November 6 - 1981 August 31 (Box 5, Folder 58)
    - Crime Reports, 1977 June 17 - 1980 January 25 (Box 5, Folder 59)
    - Crime Statistics, 1975 September 29 - 1981 July 9 (Box 6, Folder 60)
    - Harassment, 1968 June 30 - 1969 November 18 (Box 6, Folder 62)
    - Library Thefts, 1972 October 23 - 1973 May 17 (Box 6, Folder 63)
    - Manual, 1972 May 4 - 1972 September 27 (Box 6, Folder 64)
    - Officers-Promotions and Reports on Officers, 1971 August 27 - 1978 May 31 (Box 6, Folder 65)
    - Retirement, 1971 August 3 - 1973 May 29 (Box 6, Folder 66)
    - Suicides, 1973 February 20 (Box 6, Folder 67)
    - Use of Firearms, 1971 December 14 - 1972 January 5 (Box 6, Folder 68)
    - Survey of Other Police Departments, in Other Universities, 1970-1971 November 16 (Box 6, Folder 69)
    - Student Patrol, 1971 September 2-8 (Box 6, Folder 70)
    - Visits to and from Police Departments, 1971 August 16-26 (Box 6, Folder 71)